JAMES CHAPMAN

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

- (216)906-9435
- Chapmanjamesg@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/james-g-chapman
- github.com/chapmanjamesg

PROFILE

After working in the restaurant industry achieving the title of manager I still found myself wanting more. I decided to go back to school and find something that I can be passionate about, which I found in the form of coding. I took multiple classes in C# and HTML/CSS and found that I really enjoyed using my imagination to create. After this realization I decided to take a chance and move 800 miles to a new city and participate in the Nashville Software School. I want to use the customer service experience that I have gained in the service industry, and combine that with my new technical skills.

EXPERIENCE

JUNIOR FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL | SEPT 2019 - PRESENT

Intensive 6-month full-time software boot camp that focuses on training full stack web development for both individual and team based projects.

- Using the proper flow of code using Git/GitHub and managing projects with GitHub projects
- Building single-page applications using React, HTML, CSS
- Experience using Bootstrap and Tachyons for styling web applications

GROUP PROJECTS

Nutshell

- With 3 teammates we created a single-page social platform that allowed users to add news articles, tasks, and share events and chat with other users
- Used React.js for presentation and JSON server for storage
- Personal contributions was to the chat and login/out features

SERVER TRAINER

BRICCO | FEB 2008- MAY 2009; NOV 2010-APR 2013; APR 2019- SEPT 2019

- Originally hired as a bus person and worked up to a bartender and server trainer
- Served tables in a fast paced restaurant
- · Managing a bar during busy nights

LEAD SERVER

SHAKER HEIGHTS COUNTRY CLUB | AUG 2017-APR 2019

- Trained all new servers
- Worked closely with members of the club to increase the skills with in the server department
- Serve during board meetings and special events
- Setup and break down parties following specified instructions

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

SEPT 2019-PRESENT | WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOT CAMP

CUYHOGA COMMUNITY COLLEGE

JULY 2016-SEPT 2019 | INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

DICKINSON COLLEGE

AUG 2005-DEC 2008 | ECONOMICS